Afsaneh Sadeghnia

Junior Java Engineer

Unlimited Work Permit in Netherlands

Parnassusweg 999, Amsterdam 1082LZ

+31 (0) 615357770

Email: x.sadeghnia@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/xsadeghnia

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/a-sadeghnia

Skype: x.sadeghnia

SUMMARY

A Java enthusiast and a fast learner with more than 8 years of IT organizational management and teaching experience regarding various programming languages and software design techniques in the best technical institute in Tehran, I'm looking for my next opportunity to make the best use of my current and future knowledge. With my speciality in web development and technologies, and the attraction of Java based solutions, I chose to be a top-notch Java engineer who proudly as an IT woman, can bring values and innovative ideas to the team and my future company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java JavaScript
- Familiar with: C#.NET PHP Python
- Web Development: HTML CSS JavaScript PHP ASP.NET MVC REST
- Object Oriented Programming: Encapsulation Inheritance Polymorphism Abstraction Interfaces Generic types Inversion of Control and Dependency Injection Design patterns like Singleton, Factory, DAO, Strategy, etc.
- Java Frameworks: JPA Hibernate JDBC Log4j Spring IoC Spring MVC Spring Boot
- Operating Systems: Windows Linux Mac OS Terminal and command line
- Databases: MySQL MS SQL Server Relational Models ER Diagram SQL
- Build Systems: Maven
- Computer Science: Algorithm Design Data Structure (Array, Stack, Queue, Linked list, Circular and double linked list)Tree, etc)
- Computer Networks: OSI Model & Internet Protocol Suite TCP UDP
- Scrum: JIRA Bitbucket Github
- Source Version Control: git
- UML: Use-Case Diagram Activity Diagram Class Diagram etc.
- Graphics: Adobe Photoshop Flash Action Script

CAREER

★ Tehran Institute of Technology

Web and Development Department Manager (Jun. 2015 - Feb. 2017)

Tehran, Iran

- Substantial growth in the annual income of the department because of introducing a number of new programs and courses
- Strategic planning and introducing new programs and products for the department

★ Tehran Institute of Technology

Product Manager (Apr. 2011 - May. 2015)

Tehran, Iran

- · Communication with teams in order to develop and deliver features necessary for workshops, classes, and programs
- Asking for feedback from customers participating in programs, workshops, and classes
- Designing new programs, workshop, and courses and asking the teams to develop the required content

★ Tehran Institute of Technology

Web and Development Instructor and Specialist (Dec. 2008 - Mar. 2011)

Tehran, Iran

- Instructing various courses, and workshops
- Content production for defined courses, programs, and workshops
- · Giving consultancy to upper management and potential customers for choosing the proper programs

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Persian (Native), English (B2)

Please read the overleaf ...

EDUCATION

• 2004 - 2006

Islamic Azad University, South Tehran Branch

Tehran, Iran

Associate Degree in Computer Software

• 2011 - 2013

University of Applied Science and Technology

Tehran, Iran

Bachelor Degree in Information Technology Engineering (Web Development)

Training and Certificates

- 2010 at *Isiran Institute*: **Core .NET fundamentals using C#** (60 hours)
- 2015 at Tehran Institute of Technology: SCJP Java Programming Essentials (70 hours)
- 2017 at British Language Training Center: English 3 (48 hours)
- 2018 at British Language Training Center: English 4 (48 hours)
- 2018 at British Language Training Center: English 5 (40 hours)
- 2018 at British Language Training Center: English Fluency A (28 hours)
- 2018 at LinkedIn Learning: Java 8 Essential Training (6 hours and 4 minutes)
- 2019 at LinkedIn Learning: Advanced Java Programming (3 hours and 33 minutes)
- 2019 at LinkedIn Learning: Java Memory Management (3 hours)
- 2019 at LinkedIn Learning: Creating your first RESTful Spring Boot Microservice with JPA (1 hours and 27 minutes)

INTERESTS

- IT Management: Agile methodologies Scrum Team management Talent management
- Cosmetics and make up: Hair coloring Hair Highlighting Make up
- Cooking: Cooking Persian and western foods and dishes